import { Quiz, QuizQuestion } from '../../types';

const PrepositionCasesQuiz: Quiz[] = [
  {
    description: 'Které podstatné jméno pád je to?',
    name: 'Předložky pády',
    questions: [
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'během' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'bez' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'do' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'kromě' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'místo' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'od' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'okolo' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'podle' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'u' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'uprostřed' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'vedle' },
      { answer: ['2'], question: 'z' },
      { answer: ['3'], question: 'díky' },
      { answer: ['3'], question: 'k' },
      { answer: ['3'], question: 'kvůli' },
      { answer: ['3'], question: 'naproti' },
      { answer: ['4'], question: 'mimo' },
      { answer: ['4'], question: 'pro' },
      { answer: ['4'], question: 'přes' },
      { answer: ['4'], question: 'skrz' },
      { answer: ['4, 6'], question: 'na' },
      { answer: ['4, 6'], question: 'o' },
      { answer: ['4, 7'], question: 'mezi' },
      { answer: ['4, 7'], question: 'nad' },
      { answer: ['4, 7'], question: 'pod' },
      { answer: ['4, 7'], question: 'před' },
      { answer: ['4, 7'], question: 'za' },
      { answer: ['6'], question: 'po' },
      { answer: ['6'], question: 'při' },
      { answer: ['6'], question: 'v' },
      { answer: ['7'], question: 's' }
    ]
  }
];

export default PrepositionCasesQuiz;
